# Md Khirul Islam Badal

# Junior Web Developer

<sup>©</sup> 8733397178 

■ badolcsejnu135@gmail.com 

Calgary, Alberta 

In LinkedIn 

Github

## **Summary**

As an experienced web developer and user interfaces, I have in-depth knowledge in HTML5, CSS3, SCSS and NodeJS, with a focus on creating responsive and cross browser compatible websites. I excel in collaborative environments, working closely with stakeholders to iterate on design and functionality, and conducting thorough code reviews, testing, QA, and debugging to maintain high code quality.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

[Bishop University]: [Graduate Teaching Assistant] [September, 2023 – December, 2023]

- Managed a group of students and classroom activities, timemanagement.
- Provided feedback on students' assignments, evaluating and reflecting on your teaching approaches.

# [Royal University]: [Lecturer]

[January, 2021 – April, 2022]

- Communicated with students to discuss academic needs. and goals in order to adjust lessons and assessments.
- Wrote progress reports and feedback to present to students and administration, working with admin to adjust student plans as needed
- Built in office hours for 2 hours per week for students to check-in and receive one-on-one help, which boosted their mastery level by 13%.

## **Projects**

## Travel Website with MERN <<u>Live</u>> <<u>Source Code</u>>

Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB

A simple tour booking website where user can find many tour package. User can book their tour from website and post their feedback on the website. User can easily create account and login the webapp for the services.

## **Implicit Learning Website <Source Code>**

Technologies: Django, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL

A Django based web application where a student can find their class lecture, extra sheet and notice of their coaching. A blog page added in the website where the teachers can write motivational lines for the students. An admin panel can update the content of the website.

## **Research & Publications**

- R. Anik, K. Islam and M. M. A. Polash, "<u>Performance Analysis and Mitigating the Challenges of Constraint-based Local Search</u>,"
- Badal, M.K.I., Saha, S. (2022). "<u>Performance Analysis of Deep Neural Network Models for Weather Forecasting in Bangladesh</u>".

### **Skills**

C, C++, Python, JavaScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Django, Docker, Git, SaaS, HTML5, Grunt

#### **Education**

- MS in Computer Science Bishops University Sherbrooke, Quebec Sept, 2022 to Dec, 2023
   Grado: 3.90 out 4.00
  - Grade: 3.90 out 4.00
- BSc in Computer Science & Engineering
  Jagannath University
  Dhaka, Bangladesh
  Jan, 2014 to Dec, 2019
  Grade: 3.57 out 4.00

#### Honors

 Awarded as 3<sup>rd</sup> position at Bracathon -II hosted by Brac Organization, Dhaka.

# **Participation**

- NSU Cybernauts 2016,
   2018 (Senior Project Contest)
- BITM (Web Design Course)
   Duration 3 Months
- I have a sound knowledge on Algorithm, Data Structure and Solved problems in different Online Judge.